

CISCO
CERTIFIED

CONA
ROUTING &
SWITCHING

Cell: 551-666-8445

abhimshah92@gmail.com

LinkedIn URL: www.linkedin.com/in/abhishekmshah

SUMMARY:

Cisco Certified Network Associate - Routing & Switching (Cisco ID: CSCO12851572)

Network Engineer - Intern at Bridgevoice Inc.

Monitored Network using SolarWinds Network Monitoring Tool

Implemented switching with redundancy and load balancing through Inter-VLAN Routing, Trunking, STP, VTP and Ether-Channel

Extensive working knowledge of routing protocols OSPF, EIGRP, RIP and basic BGP

Good understanding of designing LAN/WAN Network and securing it with port security

Proficient in IP Addressing, sub-netting, TCP/IP and UDP Protocols, and other applications such as DHCP, DNS, Telnet, SSH, SNMP, NTP

Expertise training in Network Designing and Implementation using CCNP R&S Labs

Working knowledge of traffic filters using access-list

Experience with Network Simulation Tools including Cisco Packet Tracer, GNS 3 Dynamips and Network management and monitoring tool Wireshark

Excellent communication skills well versed in interacting with individuals as well as working effectively with groups

EDUCATION:

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJMay 2016Masters of Science, Telecommunications ManagementGPA: 3.7Shah & Anchor Kutchhi Engineering College, Mumbai University, IndiaJune 2014Bachelors of Engineering, Computer EngineeringGPA: 3.2

SKILLS/CERTIFICATIONS:

Certifications: Cisco Certified Network Associate - Routing & Switching, Cisco ID: CSC012851572 August 2015 – August 2018

Network Simulators/Analyzer: Wireshark, Cisco Packet Tracer, GNS3, SolarWinds, SmarterTrack

Routing & Switching: EIGRP, OSPF, RIP, HSRP, VRRP, GLBP, MPLS, STP, RSTP, PVST, MSTP, Ether Channel, Port Security, AAA, VLANs,

Trunking, VPN

Applications: IP Addressing, Sub-netting, TCP/IP, DHCP, DNS, SNMP, ACL, NAT, SMTP, LDAP, TELNET, SSH, Active Directory, SSL,

ping, nslookup, traceroute, netstat, tcpdump

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux – Ubuntu, CentOS

Soft Skills: MS PowerPoint, MS Excel, MS Word, MS Visio, Basic Java & C++

EXPERIENCE:

Bridgevoice Inc, Kew Gardens, NY February 2016 – Present

Network Engineer - Intern

- Understood Network architecture and prepared network resolution reports with basic analysis
- Support senior Network Engineer in troubleshooting network issues
- Monitor network using SolarWinds Network Performance Monitor & Server and Application Performance Monitor
- Install Operating System (CentOS) on Servers
- Handle tickets using SmarterTrack Ticketing Tool and ensure technical escalation, where appropriate

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ

September 2014 - Present

Graduate Teaching Assistant, Telecommunications Management

- Conduct and upload exams on Canvas for more than 125 students including graduate and undergraduate students
- Grade exams as well as demonstrate solutions for students
- Examine technical papers of graduate level students
- Assist professor in administrative work and to create exams for three Graduate level courses
- Interact with students in group as well as individually to help them in course work

West India Avenue, Mumbai, India

May 2013 - May 2014

Network Engineer - Intern

- Monitored and troubleshot LAN and generated weekly reports
- Configured Cisco Switches and Routers
- Observed network performance and reported to the incident manager
- Assisted lead networking engineer in areas of configuration, testing and implementation

TRAINING:

RST Forum, Mumbai, India June 2015 – August 2015

Cisco Certified Network Professional - Routing & Switching Training

- Configured Routers and Switches based on CCNP R&S Labs to create LAN/WAN Design
- Designed and implemented Routing and Switching scenarios in Lab Environment
- Monitored Cisco Routers and Switches using different show commands
- Implemented EIGRP initial configuration, load balancing and variance, stub, authentication and redistribution
- · Performed OSPF initial configuration, authentication, stub, redistribution and virtual link
- Implemented switching by performing STP, Trunking, Inter VLAN Routing, VTP, Ether Channel, HSRP, VRRP and GLBP
- Analyzed and troubleshot Cisco Routers and Switches in LAN/WAN scenario
- Secured ports using Port Security and Authentication to prevent unauthorized access to the network

PROJECTS/PRESENTATIONS:

Cisco Packet Tracer Labs

- Designed LAN/WAN network using CCNP Labs
- Configured Routers and Switches with static routes and dynamic routes using EIGRP, RIPv2 and OSPF
- Tested telnet connection, implemented banner and secured routers and switches
- · Implemented switching with redundancy and load balancing

Network Designing - West India Avenue

January 2014 - March 2014

- Designed prototype of the network
- Assigned IP addresses to the devices in network
- Implemented ether channel and trunking on cisco switches
- Performed Inter VLAN Routing between different VLANs

ACTIVITIES:

Active on the Cisco Learning Network

Teaching Assistant of Telecommunications Management (Graduate Program) and Business Technology (Undergraduate Program)

Volunteered in Mumbai University Blood Donation Camp

Active member of Indian Graduate Student Association

Organized Technical and Non-Technical Events at Shah & Anchor Kutchhi Engineering College